["Lazarus" playing]
♪ Look up here I'm in heaven ♪
♪ I've got scars that can't be seen ♪
♪ I've got drama, can't be stolen ♪
♪ Everybody knows me now ♪
He was in the war.
He was in a tunnel collapse.
[exhaling]
He won medals.
Take care of him.
♪ Look up here, man, I'm in danger ♪
♪ I've got nothing left to lose ♪
♪ I'm so high, it makes my brain whirl ♪
♪ Dropped my cell phone down below ♪
[door opens]
[nurse] Here he is, Mr. Shelby.
[Michael] Thank you, nurse.
Tommy.
I need to speak to you about the priest.
[breathing heavily]
I know things about him.
Hmm.
From when I was a…
From when I was a boy.
I will shoot him myself, Tommy.
Just teach me how to shoot.
[scoffs]
It's easy, Michael.
Just point.
Pull the trigger.
[door opens]
[infant cooing]
[exhales]
[door opens and closes]
[footsteps approaching]
He asked for me today, Mary.
Not his mother.
For the first time.
He missed you.
Where is he? Is he in the kitchen?
Yes, he's with the girls and Johnny.
[clears throat]
Did you remember your medicine, sir?
Do you ever read the Bible, Mary?
Sometimes.
Do you ever read it out loud
while standing naked next to my bed?
'Cause when I take the morphine
the doctor gave me,
that's what you do.
I'm wide awake,
but you are standing there naked,
plain as day,
reading from the Book of Leviticus.
Do you wanna know what happens next?
No.
Neither do I.
That's why I poured the medicine away.
Go and get Johnny, Mary.
-[imperceptible yelling]
-[electric guitar playing]
-[imperceptible]
-[sniffles]
Without the firing pins,
the guns won't work.
And there are no replacements?
They don't make these anymore.
These are the end of the line.
Yeah, we had the foreman take out
all the spares.
Take the pins, they'll never fire a shot.
Nobody will know until they unload
the bloody things in Tbilisi.
Or until they are facing our guns
at Kutaisi.
Take them all out and give them to me.
Oh, come on, boys, no fucking about.
And I will tell the Soviet Ambassador
that there is no longer a need
to blow up the train.
[Arthur]
I will tell Tommy you accept his plan.
[spits]
[Johnny]
You know, some mornings I wake up,
I think I've died and this is heaven, Tom.
[chuckles]
I mean, the wives and kids camped out
by the valley, huh, not being moved on.
Sure, me and myself. I'm surrounded
by maids and food and booze. [chuckles]
See that line there?
No.
It's the edge of heaven.
The border
between Birmingham and paradise.
And today, my friend, you are gonna
step over that line back into the world.
You mean you have something
for me to do, Tom.
Have you ever heard
of Hampton Court Palace, Johnny?
No. I can't say I have.
You and three families of the Lees
are gonna set up camp
100 yards from the gate of the Palace.
You won't be moved on
because I have just bought the land.
You'll be joined
by some old friends of mine
who are gonna open a hole
underneath your tents and caravans.
You see this blow to the head
you took, Tom…
And for allowing the hole to be dug,
you will get ₤5,000,
which you will split between
the three Lee families.
I take a lot of this money is to do with
not asking questions, Tommy?
Dead right, Johnny.
And when the hole is filled in again,
you can go back to paradise.
[sighs]
[Mary] Mr. Shelby, your brothers are here.
And there is someone who described himself
as the "Wandering Jew."
[groans slowly]
Will you take the Jewish gentleman
to the drawing room?
Take my brothers to the kitchen
and give them tea and rum. [clears throat]
[Mary] Yes, sir.
[door opens]
Good morning, Mr. Solomons.
Yeah, it is.
Nice little place you've got here, Thomas.
What is it?
A foreclosure of a gambling debt
from some poor young lord
who you pumped full of opium
in one of your casinos?
Or is that just tittle-tattle?
Drink?
Nah, I don't touch it, mate.
Your housekeeper said
you're not allowed to drink.
Eh?
She said you are suffering from so many
ancient injuries from your sporting life
that your head is like
some sort of smashed vase
what has been stuck back together
by a horse.
Now.
Word in London is that you can be found
wandering the streets of Birmingham
stark naked, throwing away money.
You talk to dead people.
Also, that you believe
that you are powerful enough
to summon up Jews…
of a very particular standing
up to the gentile wilderness
wherein you live
in order for them
to do your fucking bidding, mate.
And still you came.
Yeah, well, you know,
I was passing, wasn't I?
Do you know something, Alfie,
this morning I tried to read the paper,
and I realized that the only consequence
of my terrible accident
is that I now need glasses.
Right.
Right. Well, I know a man…
who can make you a pair of these.
He is a magician, mate.
He is a magician.
So not only will you be able
to read your newspaper…
but you will also be able to see
into the future.
Now, I know this, right,
because he made this pair here for me.
So you don't have to worry
about telling me what this is all about,
because I have already seen it.
You're fucking about with Russians,
isn't you, you silly boy?
You've got two choices, Michael.
You fuck off to America with Arthur,
join the Apaches,
-or you marry the girl.
-This isn't a joke.
Arthur, are you really gonna live
with the Apaches?
-Told her father yet?
-No.
He'll fucking shoot you, man.
Are you sure the kid's yours?
[Michael sighs] I wish I hadn't told you.
Then think of marriage
as a beautiful road,
flowers all the way down it.
-Is he joking?
-Oh, it's hard to tell these days.
Do you, uh…
Do you love the woman?
Fucking what?
Go and marry her like the rest of us.
She doesn't want her family to know.
She doesn't wanna have the baby.
-We know a woman.
-Shut up, John.
Same woman who helped you out twice.
-Not my women.
-Mmm-hmm?
That's why you had them fixed, Arthur.
Charlotte will want the best.
-[John] She is the best.
-The best?
She used to be a nurse. 20minutes. Done.
You don't have to go to in
or wait outside.
You go to The Garrison,
drink whiskey, have a laugh.
Remember, John?
Then this kid walks in, no shoes on,
says, "It's done."
Second time we was in there, same kid.
This time he's wearing… shiny new shoes.
-He shouts, "It's done, Arthur."
-And what?
She bought new shoes…
with the money I gave her.
It was for a good cause.
[Johnny] Arthur?
If you're gonna get on like this
with the Apaches,
they'll fucking scalp you, boy.
[bell ringing]
Tommy said when that bell rings
we're to all go to the big room.
Come on. Tommy has a plan.
-Arthur!
-[inhales sharply]
-Arthur?
-[Tommy] Arthur, come here.
-[Alfie] Shalom!
-[groans]
Arthur, shalom.
-Alfie.
-Shalom.
Come here. Come. Let's sit down.
I owe you a little something, don't I?
I do. Come on.
Sit down. Come on, sit down here.
[grunting] There you go.
Right.
Listen.
Arthur.
I want you to know that whatever happened
between us back then, that was business.
It was just business. All right?
And I also want you to know that I have
made my apologies via my own God
for abusing a very holy day to get you
clinked up and battered, which I did.
And now I would also like to extend
my personal apologies unto you.
All right?
I hear that you have allowed Jesus
to come into your life.
Eh?
Oh, you heard then.
Yeah, that's beautiful, that's wonderful.
That is lovely, isn't it?
That is lovely.
And I was wondering, how does that
work for you on a day to day
considering your line of work, mate?
Your apology is accepted.
'Cause I hear
you're a right fucking nuisance with it.
-[chuckles]
-[inhales sharply]
Hello…
You see, all I am saying is that
every man, he craves certainty,
doesn't he?
He craves a certainty
even if that certainty of yours, right…
Well, I mean…
It's fucking fanciful mate, isn't it?
[seething]
Eh?
I'm Old Testament.
Fucking hell. Look at that. Now, that…
That scares me more.
Yeah. Congratulations, Tommy.
You now have the finished article
right here, don't you?
See, that man, right, he will murder
and maim for you with God on his side.
Yeah.
You don't wanna let him go.
If we're gonna do business
with this fucker, I demand to know why.
[Tommy] Right. [sighs]
While I was in the hospital,
I formulated a plan,
and this is how it's gonna work.
So, the Russians
cannot be trusted to pay us.
We are gonna take what is ours.
We need to see what's in their treasury.
And that is why we need Mr. Solomons.
["Cherry Lips" playing]
[sighs] All right, boys, just remember
they're fucking insane.
And dangerous
and drunk on stuff we've never heard of.
And they're worse than us
for spirits and ghosts.
Today they're gonna test us.
Fuck them.
[Arthur] The Russians all turned and ran.
The Cossacks didn't run, Arthur.
Mr. Shelby, welcome.
-How's my car?
-I think I'm in love with it.
And I yours.
So we should keep what we love, yes?
Excuse the reception. Whenever we open
the treasury, the Cossacks are on guard.
[spits]
[Tommy] In Russia, men on the other side
of the law decorate their body in tattoos.
-Nice.
-Right.
Now, some of these tattoos are proof of
allegiance to underground organizations,
which are the sworn enemies
of the royal household.
So, it's customary
in Russian royal households
to check for such tattoos
before engaging a man in business.
And as we approach the allotted day,
these ladies here
would like to make sure that
you're not assassins or infiltrators…
No, we are all good.
So they would like to check your skin.
-They wanna check our skin?
-Yeah.
Now, my body's already been checked.
Although at the time,
I wasn't sure that was the reason.
And now it's your turn.
Come on, boys. Take your clothes off.
[scoffs]
Fuck off.
No, no, no.
Obey.
I see.
Obey, Arthur.
No, I won't be obeying nobody.
Get out of my way, both of you.
Arthur, come here.
[in Romany]
I told you they're all fucking mad.
They're only half joking.
Let the ladies have their fun.
Eh? Eh?
[John speaking English]
Come on, Arthur. [chuckling]
-[Arthur] Shut up, John.
-[John laughs]
[Tatiana laughs]
I will have a maid gather the buttons
and sew them back on.
[in Russian] Remember he is the most
dangerous. The other one the prettiest.
All right.
Fuck it.
There you go, ladies.
-Made in fucking Birmingham.
-[John laughs]
All right, I think
we have seen enough, eh?
Tatiana.
[John snickers]
Your face, Arthur, is a fucking picture.
Sometimes assassins hide their allegiances
behind their balls.
[breathes deeply]
[John continues snickering]
But you pass the test, soldier.
With flying colors.
-[John chuckles]
-[moans softly]
You see.
[breathing heavily]
He wants to be a good man.
But there now.
There.
Inside every man there is a devil.
[moans softly]
-They're real diamonds, eh?
-[Tatiana sighs]
[Izabella] It is traditional to
seal the successful examination
with vodka and music.
[John laughing]
Holy fuck, Tom. What was that?
Well done, boys. Eh?
Well done, Arthur.
Now you know what we have to do next.
All right?
One last job.
Make contact and play nice.
Another five minutes.
I brought Michael because as
chief accountant he has to be witness.
Ada, can I, uh, use your phone?
Michael.
Business first.
Michael, stop looking at your watch.
Ada, whilst you are reading this, um,
can I go and use your phone?
Who is the lucky girl, Michael?
Her name is Charlotte,
and Michael cannot breathe
if he does not talk to her
every two hours.
Ada, please.
Phone's in the hall.
-Dial naught for the line.
-Thank you.
And keep it quick, I pay the bill.
-I will.
-Not for long.
[Ada chuckles]
[breathing deeply]
Think about it, Pol.
Together we can take control.
With two of us in the company,
we can straighten things out.
What about the politics?
You and me fighting together and winning,
that is politics.
That's a new kind of politics.
It is just this way I get paid
and Karl gets a nice Christmas.
Good. Welcome to the bourgeoisie.
[chuckles]
My name is Smith.
Uh…
My girlfriend is pregnant.
And, uh,
we'd like you to help us.
We need to fix a date.
Welcome to Shelby Company Limited.
Shelby Company Limited.
-Limited and unarmed.
-[door opens]
Michael, would you like to welcome Ada,
our new Head of Property and Acquisitions.
Congratulations.
Where do I sign?
[clears throat]
Ada, have you got, um, whiskey?
Yeah, Tommy.
I've already told him.
He's becoming too like his cousin.
[Michael] I thought that was the idea.
Yeah, Tommy but with a bit
more fucking charm and class.
Yeah.
-[sarcastically] Hmm, that'll help.
-Yep.
-Where am I sleeping, Ada?
-Michael…
-In the room next to Karl's.
Good night!
-[door slams]
-Oh.
Heartbroken, poor love.
So, how shall we celebrate?
Well, with Michael in bed,
I thought I might, um…
go for a little drive.
Drive? Where are you gonna drive?
Polly?
Things have begun to develop
with the man who is painting my portrait.
Polly?
It's…
It's when you stand there in the dress,
you just find yourself talking
about every little thing.
And have you…
-No.
-Mmm?
-Not yet.
-[chuckles]
But he called me two nights ago
to say that the portrait was finished,
and I said I'd go there in the morning.
But he said no,
he wanted me there tonight.
Ada, you don't breathe a fucking word
of this to the boys.
[giggles] Okay, but is he nice to you?
No… No, I mean it Ada.
Is he rich?
His friends write the papers, Ada.
Tommy would try and close him down.
-So go.
-[chuckles]
He's like a tiny bird pecking at you,
and I think he's given up on me.
So bloody go.
Why should the boys have all the fun?
[chuckles]
[music playing]
-[imperceptible conversations]
-[women moaning]
[sniffs]
More vodka.
-[woman moaning]
-[imperceptible shouting]
Wait there.
You're doing good, Stefan.
It's a fucking madhouse.
Yeah, I know.
The Prince wants me to suck his cock.
[snickers]
How much would you need to say yes?
That's on top of the day rate
for the ass slaps.
When am I out of here?
Soon.
[clears throat] What you got?
The strong room is not guarded at night,
but they said they will kill
the three brothers in the Ugolnyi dvor.
Coal yard.
The Duke was talking about using a sword,
but the woman,
she was talking about using machine guns.
[groans]
[Stefan sobbing]
It's a fucking madhouse, John.
We're doing up your pub in Nechells.
It looks a treat.
Keep your fucking head up, Peaky boy, eh?
Fucking madhouse, man.
We are almost there. This way.
This treasury was built 200 years ago
to protect the King's jewels
in case of French invasion.
We are now underneath the River Thames.
[dog barking]
[snarls and barks]
Your jeweler.
I, I… I don't think they trust me, Tommy.
Mr. Solomons is the only jeweler
I trust in London.
Yes. "Trust". Yes.
Might have to add that on the old invoice.
[grunts]
Thank you.
As we agreed, your jeweler will now
select items to a total value of £70,000.
When you have selected your chosen items,
they will be put into a box and stored.
When you have fulfilled
your part of the deal,
the box will be delivered to you.
May I just start, right, by saying
that I may choose to stay here
and just starve to death
and choke on sapphires.
I'd have never go back
to the fucking world again.
[in Russian]
The Jew smells of rum.
[in English] There is a good reason
for that, you know, little man.
Because my shop, right,
is just above a rum house.
-So all them…
-You speak Russian?
Yeah, I do, 'cause of me mum.
Yeah, me mother.
You people, all right,
you hunted my mum with dogs
through the snow.
Yeah.
But today, right,
is for forgiveness, isn't it?
For selection.
So, now, hello, right…
I think it is fair to say, yeah, £1,500.
-£1,500?
-All right, I will give you £1,800.
[Izabella] I know
the current market value. £1,800 it is.
That's very gracious of you.
All right then.
Now, let's have a look at this.
This is a nice little bit, isn't it?
[stutters]
But that was a gift of Tsar Nicholas.
I aren't asking you that though, am I?
I aren't asking you, all right?
I come here to do business,
for my professional services.
If you keep interrupting me
I won't be able to focus too much.
Do you understand?
Mr. Romanov, let me remind you
we were told to come here
to choose what we like
and now we have chosen.
Tsar Nicholas gave you that.
I will give you £4,000.
£5,000 with the royal provenance.
Done.
Right, Rumplestiltskin, let's go over here
and have a look what's in these boxes.
£2,000…
That's much nicer. £10,000.
That's definitely a five.
-Are you keeping score?
-Yes, I am.
-Another £5,000.
-£7,000.
-£6,000…
-Let's call it £6,000, eh?
-Beauty. Look at that.
-[Leon] Beautiful, isn't it?
-[Alfie] That is splendid.
-[Leon] Splendid, yes.
It is beautiful, is it not?
-It is.
-It is a work of art.
-You recognize this work, do you?
-Immediately.
I'm guessing, right, that all
the bad ideas around here, they're you.
Right, they are you, aren't they? Hmm?
-How could you mean…
-Yeah, all right. Tommy, see this, right?
It's got paste in it. That's paste.
Let me tell you something, son.
If somebody comes into my shop
with some paste like this,
usually what I make them do, right,
-is fucking swallow it. Eh?
-No.
What game are you playing?
-Eh?
-Uh, Mr. Solomons…
[speaking other language]
[in English]
Shall we, uh… Shall we clean it up?
-[speaking other language]
-Eh?
Hmm?
[in English] Yeah. Yes.
Right, what have we got?
£37,600.
Well…
Do you have any eggs?
Excuse…
I am simply asking…
Fabergé is not part of the deal.
We would not offer you Fabergé eggs…
Mr. Romanov, my jeweler here,
he advises me to insist on Fabergé.
It's a deal breaker, Tommy.
Oh, hell…
I brought that from Crimea myself.
Fucking hell…
With the provenance of that being laid
by such a delicate beauty,
that does indeed bring
the entire selection to £70,000.
[spits]
[exhales sharply]
-Good man.
-And now, Mr. Shelby,
you will join your brothers
and Mr. Solomons will take his leave.
I demand absolute honesty.
-Oh, sorry, can I…
-I insist.
There.
A woman of style and substance.
I am a student of silence.
Is this good silence or bad silence?
It's good.
[chuckles]
-It's very good.
-No! It's still wet.
I know it isn't saying much
in the grand scheme of things,
but this is the best work I've ever done.
I'll miss Sundays.
There'll be more Sundays.
Sorry. Sorry, can you not do that, please?
-Can you just not do that, please?
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
It's all right if it's the mouth. It's…
[folk music playing]
[imperceptible shouting]
[woman laughing]
Vodka.
I sewed your buttons back on.
I wanted to see if I did a good job.
Yeah, you did.
You did a good job.
Sir?
No, I didn't.
[woman and man moaning]
My aunt only employs the best whores.
How did you feel when I held him?
You were jealous.
You wanted to kill me or him.
No?
Why do you play games with people…
when there is no benefit to you?
In Russia, because we were bored.
In England,
because… we don't know how to stop.
At least, they are silly games
and orgasms.
-So let's fuck.
-Here?
Uh…
No, in a darker place.
[in Russian]
Damn!
Whores!
Goddamned!
-[moaning]
-[breathing heavily]
[both breathing heavily]
You still love her, don't you?
You want her?
Why would you fucking say that?
Why would you fucking say it?
Tommy, you love her.
-What are you fucking saying?
-You want her?
-[grunts]
Who the fuck are you, eh?
Hmm?
[sobs] What are you fucking saying?
What the fuck…
[grunts]
[sobbing]
You want her… tonight?
Watch…
In the palace in Tbilisi,
there was a priest.
And he would put his hands here.
And with that strangulation,
there was also ecstasy.
It's called Khlysty. A Siberian prayer.
You are almost hung over.
You are almost dead.
But in that moment…
[inhales sharply]
[moans]
Women who had lost men in the war
would lay down,
and they would fuck the ghost.
-You want her.
-[choking]
You want her, don't you?
You want her!
[gasps]
[both grunting]
["You Want It Darker" playing]
♪ If you are the dealer
I'm out of the game ♪
♪ If you are the healer
It means I'm broken and lame ♪
♪ If thine is the glory
Then mine must be the shame ♪
♪ You want it darker ♪
[gasping]
♪ We kill the flame ♪
Now you should drink this.
-It's holy water.
-Get the fuck away from me.
There.
I opened up another treasury for you.
[panting]
You should call this painting…
"Fuck Them All!"
[laughing]
I will.
The parish, the King,
the copper.
Yeah, the copper in particular.
Do you want to hear the wildest story
of them all?
Yes.
I killed a policeman in cold blood.
With a gun.
Really?
She did it.
["Monkey 23" playing]
♪ There's a monkey on my back ♪
♪ Makes me talk like that ♪
♪ Makes me act like that ♪
♪ There's a monkey on my back ♪
♪ Makes me talk like that ♪
[John] Whoa.
I tell you what.
I tell you what, I swear at one point…
At one point I looked down,
I got the top of her head,
and I thought she was gonna pull
me cock off in her hand
and fucking throw it out of the window.
Oh!
She sucked me dry, I swear to God.
Like fucking spud water at the end.
We've had worse nights. [clears throat]
-You're quiet, Arthur, eh?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Fuck off.
-How was your night, brother?
-You got all your buttons back, eh?
-Yeah, all right, fuck off…
Yeah, what's God gonna say
about it, Arthur?
Fuck off, both of ya.
[sighs]
He tells Linda everything.
Every single thing.
Yeah well, we'll see.
We're gonna miss you
when you're gone, now, Arthur.
Just drive the fucking car.
[engine starting]
Private Letso reporting for duty,
Sergeant Major.
At ease, Private.
Good to see you.
[Arthur] Seven left out of 50.
Should I get them tea?
Get 'em beer, Curly.
They used to run on it
like cars on petrol.
Give 'em the black country stuff.
It's in a barrel with the tack.
[grunts]
They're gonna fucking clean me out.
Whatever they take, they will put back.
They're good men.
John, Arthur. You remember these boys?
Well, if it ain't the Tipton fucking
clay kickers, eh? [chuckles]
-Clay kickers.
-Come here, you all.
[imperceptible]
This is William Letso.
From the South African Native Labor Corps.
Sent to Flanders
from the Bloemfontein diamond mines.
The best tunneler I ever met.
So, there's three cellars
underneath the house.
Wine, kitchen, septic.
There's a tunnel here that runs
from the house underneath the river
to an underground strong room.
Now, this used to be the palace treasury.
The tunnel runs directly west
and it's separated from the house
by three iron doors with locks
we can't open.
We need our tunnel to run from here
and hit the strong room direct.
[keys jingling]
[door opens]
Primrose Hill 23. Ada Thorne.
Ada?
Is Michael still there?
Right, would you tell him
that I have taken the car?
He can take the train.
Will you try and find out
why he's been so bloody sour lately?
[phone clicks]
[door opens]
[Tommy clears throat]
[sighs]
You shouldn't go looking through
other people's private things.
He's my son.
The bullet was mine.
I never got a chance to fire it.
And the gypsy rules
say it must be passed on…
It's not about rules, Pol.
It's about he asked me.
It's about he told me
why he wanted to do it.
And if I tell you,
I can't take the knowledge back.
Better off without it.
So this is when he was with the parish…
Better off without it, Pol.
This is when he was with the fathers.
This is when he was in the care
of the holy fathers.
Michael wants it that you don't know.
That priest…
That priest who was there
when he was taken in,
and who is still
walking the fucking earth.
Fuck…
-Fuck…
-He asked me, Pol,
and I said yes.
And I said, "You put a bullet
in that fucker's brains."
By order of the Peaky Blinders.
[sniffles]
[sighs]
No.
Not my son.
He'll still be as dead if Arthur does it.
And part of him will always stay dead.
-I swear to God…
-In whose house it took place…
If my son pulls the trigger,
I will bring this whole fucking
organization down around your ears.
["Red Right Hand" playing]